Guide to the Frank Traver De Vyver Papers, 1899-1980 UA.29.02.0161
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1899-1980, 9 boxes
  - Collective Bargaining--Address by George Baldanzi, 1948 July 31 (Box 10)
  - Collective Bargaining--North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company's Bargaining Agreement, 1973 Apr. 1 (Box 10)
  - Collective Bargaining--When Foreman and Steward Bargain--manual, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Communists in Labor Relations Today, 1946 Mar. 28 (Box 10)
  - Coombs, N. D.--Comparative Summary of Unemployment Insurance Laws and Their Application in Five Selected States, 1948 May 11 (Box 10)
  - Cone Mills Corporation, Greensboro, NC--clippings, 1955 (Box 10)
  - Cotton textile mills wage analyses, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Davies, David George, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
  - de Kock, Alan, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Dewey, Donald, 1924-1925 (Box 10)
  - Dickens, Robert L., 1949-1963, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Distinguished Professor booklet--named professorships, bulletins, and Ph.D. booklet, 1961-1979, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Douwaji, Marina Tranjan, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Dr. de Vyver's Collection of Franklin D. Roosevelt material--Goldwater appraisal, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
  - Duke Press Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - Durham County Citizens' Council Inc., 1962-1973 (Box 10)
  - Durham County Hospital Corporation, 1971-1974 (Box 10)
  - Economic Education: The Challenge for the 70s--1972 Conference of the Australian Commercial Teachers Association, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Employers Associations article--peer review and correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Employment Security, 1950-1952, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Erwin Cotton Mills Co., 1932-1954, 23 folders
    Variety of materials about Erwin Cotton Mills Company (known as Erwin Mills after 1950), including collective bargaining agreements, analyses of jobs and personnel, and extensive clippings about strikes, especially the strike of 1945-1946. De Vyver served as the company's Vice-President of Personnel and Labor Relations from 1945-1955. For related material in the Rubenstein Library, see the Erwin Cotton Mills Records, 1832-1976, parts of which were received as a gift from De Vyver.
    - Agreement with Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), 1941 Oct. 15 (Box 10)
    - Analyses of Mills Pay Rolls, 1945 (Box 10)
    - Binder of clippings and correspondence, disbound, 1945-1946, 8 folders (Box 10)
    - Erwin Cotton Mills Co. vs. TWUA, 1944-1953 (Box 11)
    - Erwin Mills, Inc.--Incentive System--Spinning, 1954 Mar. 2 (Box 11)
    - Erwin Mills, Inc.--Incentive System--Carding, 1954 Mar. 2 (Box 11)
    - Job Analysis, 1939 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda on job and time standards, 1945-1946 (Box 11)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 11)
    - Proposed Wage Increase, 1942 (Box 11)
    - Rate and earnings data, 1942-1953 (Box 11)
    - Report on Industrial Relations in the Erwin Mills, Inc., 1952 (Box 11)
    - Statement to the National War Labor Board on TWUA vs. Erwin Cotton Mills Co., 1944 (Box 11)
    - Strike, 1932, 1942-1946 (Box 11)
    - Strike clippings, 1945-1954 (Box 11)
    - Unemployment Compensation Commission of North Carolina, Decision of the Chairman, 1944 Feb. 25 (Box 11)
    - Erwin Scab Special and other clippings (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Extent of Trade Unionism in the South--material, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Federal Advisory Council, 1947-1954, 6 folders
    - Agenda, 1949 Sept. 14-15 (Box 11)
    - Committees on Disqualification and Benefit Financing, 1953-1954 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, papers, and reports, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Minutes and papers, 1949-1950 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, papers, and reports, 1951-1952 (Box 11)
    - Papers, 1947-1949 (Box 11)
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service--Statement of Arbitration Functions and Facilities, 1948 May 17 (Box 11)
  - Federal-State Employment Service, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Ferguson, C.E., 1952-1963, Folder 1 of 3 (Box 11)
  - Ferguson, C.E., 1952-1963, Folders 2-3 of 3 (Box 12)
  - Ford Gerontological Grant--Socio-Economic Studies of Aging, 1958-1960, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Ford Gerontological Grant--budgets and financial reports, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
  - Ford Foundation--Socio-Economic Studies of Aging--abstracts, correspondence, minutes, and reports, 1960-1963 (Box 12)
  - Foundation for Better Health of Durham, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Foundation for Better Health of Durham--Fund Better Health Campaign, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - The Free Market--A Struggle for Survival, by Emerson P. Schmidt, 1951 Dec. 27 (Box 12)
  - Fulbright Award, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Galifianakis, Nick, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
  - General Motors Corporation, 1945-1949 (Box 12)
  - General Motors Corporation--Third Conference for College and University Educators, 1947 June 16-30 (Box 12)
  - General Motors Corporation--Fourth Conference for College and University Educators, 1948 June 16-29 (Box 12)
  - Gerhard, Hans W., 1958-1965 (Box 12)
  - German Labor Relations, 1951, 1954 (Box 12)
  - Gift, Richard, 1965-1971 (Box 12)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd W., 1958-1962 (Box 12)
  - Graduate School of Princeton University, Address by Rep. Samuel K. McConnell, Jr.--Labor-Management Legislation, 1953 Sept. 17 (Box 12)
  - Grievance Procedure Manual by U.S. Department of Labor, 1943 (Box 12)
  - Gross, Paul Magnus, 1961-1968 (Box 12)
  - Gross, Paul Magnus--Gross-Edens Controversy, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Gross, Paul Magnus--1965 Spring Symposium in Honor of Dr. Paul M. Gross, 1964-1966 (Box 12)
  - Hamilton, Jamie R., 1980 (Box 12)
  - Hanna, Frank Allen, 1948-1961, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Hawaii Employers Council--Group Life Insurance Plans in Hawaii, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Health Affairs, 1970-1974 (Box 12)
  - Holden, Merle and Holden, Paul, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Hoover, Calvin Bryce, 1925, 1933-1935, 1948-1966, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Hoover Commission Recommendations--Statutes or Agencies Affecting Business, 1954 Nov. 20 (Box 12)
  - Howard, Bill--Laffer Volume, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - Hunter, M.S., 1939 (Box 12)
  - Industrial Relations--Australia, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Industrial Relations--Industrial Relations Positions as Approved by the NAM Board of Directors, 1950 Sept. 22 (Box 13)
  - Industrial Relations--Industrial Relations Section, 1939-1940 (Box 13)
  - Industrial Relations--Proposed Industrial Relations Programs, undated (Box 13)
  - Insurance, medical--articles on, 1947-1950 (Box 13)
  - International Labor Conference, 1950 (Box 13)
  - International Labor Organization (ILO)--Meeting of the ILO Governing Body, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Joerg, Frederiak Charles, 1950-1963 (Box 13)
  - Johnson, Walter Livezey, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1966-1970 (Box 13)
  - Keller, Thomas Franklin, 1957-1963 (Box 13)
  - King, Charles Conaway, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Knight, Douglas M., 1963-1969, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Kreps, Juanita M., 1955-1963 (Box 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations--National Labor Relations Board, 1948 (Box 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations--a Bill to Amend the Labor Management Act, 1947, 1954 Jan. 11 (Box 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations--Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Act, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations--Report of the Joint Committee on Labor-Management Relations, Congress of the United States, 1952 May 14 (Box 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations--Statement of Arthur J. Goldberg, 1954 Jan. 27 (Box 13)
  - Labor Relations Committee (LRC)--Recommendations and Rationale of the LRC, undated (Box 13)
  - Landon, Charles Earl, 1958-1961 (Box 13)
  - Leaper, John, 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Locke, John Rae Jr., 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Maafo, Eugene Victor, 1971-1975 (Box 13)
  - Maddock, Rod, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Malaysia and Singapore, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - McGee, John S., 1961-1963 (Box 13)
  - Menefee, John, 1973-1975 (Box 13)
  - Merit System Council of North Carolina--Supervisor of Merit Examinations, 1938-1945 (Box 13)
  - Mills and Mill Workers--articles and pictures, 1899, 1920-1927, 1943 (Box 13)
  - Morefield, Roger, 1976 (Box 13)
  - Monash University faculty of economics and politics--lecture notes on Labor Relations by Dianne Yerbury, 1970 (Box 13)
  - Morin, Bernard Arthur, 1964-1967 (Box 13)
  - National Association of Manufacturers (NAM)--Law Department Memos and minutes, 1950-1953 (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation, 1962 (Box 13)
  - National Wage Stabilization Board--The Administration, Under Collective Bargaining, of Welfare Plans Based on Employers' Contributions, 1946 Sept. 18 (Box 13)
  - National War Labor Board--Handbook of Organization, Procedures, Functions, 1942-1943 (Box 13)
  - National War Labor Board--Manual of Decisions, 1943 (Box 13)
  - Naylor, Thomas H., 1963 (Box 14)
  - Negro A & T College (i.e., North Carolina A & T University) study, 1941 (Box 14)
  - New Jersey State Federation of Labor, Address of Arthur P. Pratt--Unemployment Compensation Programs, 1946 Dec. 16-18 (Box 14)
  - North Carolina Business Index by the Bureau of Research and Statistics of the Unemployment Compensation Commission, 1942, 1945 (Box 14)
  - North Carolina Cotton Manufacturers' Association, Inc.--Fringe Benefits Survey for North Carolina Cotton Manufacturers', Inc., 1951 Feb. (Box 14)
  - Northrup, Herbert R.--Management Organization--The Keystone of Sound Industrial Relations, 1954 Oct. 28 (Box 14)
  - NROTC Cruise--USS Worcester, 1953 Summer (Box 14)
  - Old age and survivors insurance, 1947-1954 (Box 14)
  - Older workers, 1954 (Box 14)
  - Open Forum on Economic and Industrial Development of the South, 1929 Aug. 5-6 (Box 14)
  - Papers--dedication events and commencement exercises, 1926-1969 (Box 14)
  - Petridis, Ray, 1968-1976 (Box 14)
  - Plan for National Joint Board for Settlement of Jurisdictional Disputes, 1948 (Box 14)
  - Powell, Burt E., 1974-1975 (Box 14)
  - Public Opinion Survey of Workers in the American and Reynolds Tobacco Companies for Duke University, by the Gallup Organization, Inc., 1967 Aug. (Box 14)
  - Pursell, Donald E., 1965-1975 (Box 14)
  - Regional Labor Supply Committee--minutes, 1941-1942 (Box 14)
  - Retirement security, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Rob, Abul K.M.A., 1973-1975 (Box 14)
  - Robinson, Albert J., 1963-1970 (Box 14)
  - Robinson, James W., 1964-1974 (Box 14)
  - Robinson, Jerald F., 1965-1971 (Box 14)
  - Roger, Joe O., 1973-1978 (Box 14)
  - The Role of Government in Social Welfare, by Eveline M. Burns, 1954 May 10 (Box 14)
  - Rutman, Gilbert L., 1963-1974 (Box 14)
  - Saville, Lloyd, 1952-1962 (Box 14)
  - Schaffer, Beverly K., 1964-1974 (Box 14)
  - Sise, A.F.--Associate Director, Personnel Relations M.I.T., 1962-1963 (Box 14)
  - Skelton, B.R., 1963-1968 (Box 14)
  - Smith, Robert S., 1955-1969 (Box 14)
  - Snare, John L., 1964-1971 (Box 14)
  - Social security, 1936-1949 (Box 14)
  - South Africa, 1937-1968, 18 folders (Box 15)
    - Constitutions and other union/ trade documents, 1937-1959 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, meetings, and reports, 1950-1968 (Box 15)
    - Economic reports, 1958-1967 (Box 15)
    - Industrial Cellulose Corporation Ltd., Bantu Consultative Committee--meeting minutes, 1958-1964 (Box 15)
    - Industrial Development Corporation of South Africa, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
    - Labor and wage materials, 1956-1960 (Box 15)
    - Milling Industry, Union of South Africa--reports, 1957 (Box 15)
    - Names, 1959-1962 (Box 15)
    - South Africa project, 1957-1960 (Box 15)
    - Specimen copies of Conciliation Board agreements, 1937-1966 (Box 15)
    - Summer, 1965-1968, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - State Department lectureship--correspondence, 1959-1967 (Box 15)
    - Tongaat Sugar Company, Limited--surveys, 1963-1967 (Box 15)
    - Torch Club speech, 1965 Feb. 17 (Box 15)
    - Transvaal Clothing Industry, 1951-1958 (Box 15)
    - Travel grant, 1966-1968 (Box 15)
  - Southeastern Personnel Conference, 1955-1963 (Box 15)
  - Southern Textile Commission, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Spengler, Joseph J., 1930-1963, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Spengler, Joseph J.--retirement dinner, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Spengler, Joseph J.--Population Economics: History of Thought, Theory, and Development. Essays of Joseph J. Spengler, 1967-1972 (Box 15)
  - State Council--Joint Council on Economic Education, 1952, 1960-1968 (Box 15)
  - State of Indiana, in the Appellate Court--Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation vs. the Review Board of the Indiana Employment Security Division, et. al., 1947 (Box 15)
  - Textile Workers Union of America--Proposed Wage Increases for the Southern Cotton Textile Industry, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Textile Workers Union of America--reports by Solomon Barkin, 1946-1956 (Box 16)
  - Textile Workers Union of America--Statement of the Textile Workers Union of America in the matter of the Cotton-Rayon Industry, 1944 Mar. 27 (Box 16)
  - Townsend, Roswell G., 1963-1968 (Box 16)
  - Troyer, Michael David, 1970-1975, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Tuthill, Richard L., 1955, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Unemployment Insurance, 1949-1959, 5 folders
    - Barber and Crouse vs. California Employment Stabilization Commission, 1954-1955 (Box 16)
    - Financing unemployment insurance, circa 1952 (Box 16)
    - Papers and reports, 1949-1959, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Unemployment insurance disqualifications, 1950-1952 (Box 16)
  - United Auto Workers--Congress of Industrial Organizations (UAW-CIO)--Is Loyalty an "Either"-"Or" Proposition, 1948 Apr. 1 (Box 16)
  - United Steel Workers of America, 1959 Apr. (Box 16)
  - Wade, Charles B., Jr.--correspondence, 1939-1945 (Box 16)
  - Wage Case: Twenty-Three Mills--papers, 1937-1945, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Wannamaker, William H., 1942-1946 (Box 16)
  - War Production Board, 1941-1943, 3 folders (Box 16)
    Correspondence, printed material, reports, and agendas related to the War Production Board, Fourth Regional Labor Supply Committee, on which De Vyver served in World War II. Materials primarily concern the potential employment and training of North Carolina workers for war industries.
  - Watts Hospital--Trustees, Personnel Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 16)
  - Watts Workers Union--material, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - Western Carolina Manufacturers Association--the North Carolina Industrial Council, 1948 May (Box 16)
  - Winfrey, John Crawford, 1964-1973 (Box 16)
  - Yohe, William P., 1957-1964 (Box 16)
  - Yonekura, Hiromasa, 1969-1971 (Box 16)
  - Unsorted miscellaneous materials, 1928-1973 and undated, 3 folders (Box 16)
- Printed Materials, 1929-1980, 2 boxes
  Loose materials, gathered into categories and formats and arranged alphabetically, beginning with reprints of articles published by De Vyver.
  - Articles by Frank De Vyver, 1930-1974, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Australian arbitration system, 1960-1970, 7 folders (Box 17)
  - Broadsides and posters, 1939, 1952-1954 (Box 17)
  - Clippings (newspaper), 1943, 1952, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Collective Bargaining agreements, 1953-1973, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box 17)
  - Collective Bargaining agreements, 1953-1973, Folder 3 of 3 (Box 18)
  - Comic books about labor, circa 1945-1948 (Box 18)
  - Newsletters, 1945-1961 (Box 18)
  - Pamphlets, 1939-1972 (Box 18)
  - Political campaigns, 1964-1969 (Box 18)
  - Reports (issued by government agencies), 1938-1972, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Reprints (articles by others), 1929-1952 (Box 18)
  - Serials, 1944-1961 (Box 18)
  - Steelworkers--articles, decisions, and pamphlets on various cases and strikes, 1946-1959, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Unsorted printed materials, 1941-1980 (Box 18)
  - Textile Workers Voice, 1949-1956 (Box 18)
  - "Textile Workers' Voice"--Communist Party, 1955 (Box 18)
  - Textile Workers Voice, April 1, 1955 (Box 18)